Guide to the Michael M. May Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Michael M. May papers
1970-2009
SC1060
May, Michael M.
Stanford University. Center for International Security and Arms Control.
18 Linear feet
The Michael M. May collection is divided into five series, although there is significant overlap between many. The primary topics include May's work for CISAC (Committee on International Security and Arms Control) - which includes research on nuclear proliferation, management of plutonium, and international relations - as well as logistical planning to do with May's travels, conferences, and papers. There are also many files dedicated to course syllabi and handouts, usually in political sciences or environmental engineering & sciences. There is one small box of reports and manuals that are restricted, having been created for the Department of Justice, Department of State, or the Department of Homeland Security; these files are restricted until January 1, 2086.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Restricted files closed until January 1, 2086. Otherwise the collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Michael May is Professor Emeritus (Research) in the Stanford University School of Engineering and a senior fellow with the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies at Stanford University. He is the former co-director of Stanford University's Center for International Security and Cooperation, having served seven years in that capacity through January 2000.
May is a director emeritus of the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, where he worked from 1952 to 1988, with some brief periods away from the Laboratory. While there, he held a variety of research and development positions, serving as director of the Laboratory from 1965 to 1971.
May was a technical adviser to the Threshold Test Ban Treaty negotiating team; a member of the U.S. delegation to the Strategic Arms Limitation Talks; and at various times has been a member of the Defense Science Board, the General Advisory Committee to the AEC, the Secretary of Energy Advisory Board, the RAND Corporation Board of Trustees, and the Committee on International Security and Arms Control of the National Academy of Sciences. He is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations and the Pacific Council on International Policy, and a Fellow of the American Physical Society and the American Association for the Advancement of Science.
May received the Distinguished Public Service and Distinguished Civilian Service Medals from the Department of Defense, and the Ernest Orlando Lawrence Award from the Atomic Energy Commission, as well as other awards.
His current research interests are nuclear weapons policy in the US and in other countries; nuclear terrorism; nuclear and other forms of energy and their impact on the environment, health and safety and security; the use of statistics and mathematical models in the public sphere.
May is continuing work on creating a secure future for civilian nuclear applications. In October 2007, May hosted an international workshop on how the nuclear weapon states can help rebuild the consensus underlying the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT). Proceedings and a summary report are available online or by email request. May also chaired a technical working group on nuclear forensics. The final report is available online.
In April 2007, May in cooperation with former Secretary of Defense William J. Perry and Professor Ashton Carter of Harvard hosted a workshop on what would have to be done to be ready for a terrorist nuclear detonation. The report is available online at the Preventive Defense Project. A summary, titled, "The Day After: Action Following a Nuclear Blast in a U.S. City," was published fall 2007 in Washington Quarterly and is available online.
Recent work also includes a study of nuclear postures in several countries (2007-2009); an article on nuclear disarmament and one on tactical nuclear weapons; and a report with Kate Marvel for the American Academy of Arts and Sciences on possible game changers in the nuclear energy industry.
Scope and Contents
The Michael M. May collection is divided into five series, although there is significant overlap between many. The primary topics include May's work for CISAC (Committee on International Security and Arms Control) - which includes research on nuclear proliferation, management of plutonium, and international relations - as well as logistical planning to do with May's travels, conferences, and papers. There are also many files dedicated to course syllabi and handouts, usually in political sciences or environmental engineering & sciences. There is one small box of reports and manuals that are restricted, having been created for the Department of Justice, Department of State, or the Department of Homeland Security; these files are restricted until January 1, 2086.
Access Terms
Stanford University. School of Engineering. Faculty..; Stanford University. School of Engineering.; Nuclear energy.; Nuclear nonproliferation.; Nuclear terrorism
Collection Contents
- CISAC (Committee on International Security and Arms Control)
  - Stares CISAC Review (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Office Information (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - APARC Faculty Affiliate (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pac. Counc. on Int'l Pol (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - W/S Further International Assurance of Fissile Mat'l Sec. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - APS Exec Bd Mtg (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CISAC Photo Orientation 10/2/00 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sci. Prog. Review (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CISAC Consulting (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - CISAC 1988-89 Corres. RE: Drell (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chernik File (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - NPS Funding (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - CISAC Financial (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - CISAC Alumni Mailing List (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Soph Sem Fund (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 2KEZ623 MacArt Wilkening (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carnegie Report (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cybersecurity (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cybersecurity (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nuc. Engy. Clim. Chng. 6/23/00 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - WAIS Award (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - WAIS Charter (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - CBW Proposal (Wilkening) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - LLNL Contract (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - DHS/ODP (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Heller-May Proposal (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - EPRI Report 1st Q 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - April 2003 Reports (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Visiting Fellows (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Wilkening 2006 Reappt. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Braun, Chaim (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Chyba, Chris (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ekaterina Drozdova (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Elliott, David (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Sy Goodman (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Zachary Haldeman (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Holloway (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Hua Di (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Kin Sing Leung (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - John Kamm (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - John Lewis (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Jenny Lind UCSD (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - DHS Award (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Lab Fmr Dir LTR 031208 Re Lab Contracts (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Workshop on Nuclear Risk Communication (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - TopOff 2 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Topoff2/T2 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Thoughts on CISAC S&T Research Agenda (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - THS Project (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Strengthening the Nonproliferation Regime: The Role of the P5 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Strategic Planning 2008 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - US Grand Strategy And Nuclear Stability: Are They Incompatible (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - An Alternative Nuclear Posture - Transparencies Incl. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Global 2005 Trip (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - US-China Strategic Dialogue Nov. 6-7, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Managing Global Insecurity: American Leadership, International Institutions, And the Search for Peace in the 21st Century - 16-17 March 2007, Stanford University (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Workshop on National Nonproliferation Controls - 27 March, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - IDA 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Preventive Defense Project - Overhauling Counterproliferation Workshop Series - Workshop 6 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - US Nuclear Weapons and Our Strategic Future (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - APS/AAAS Report 2008 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University - Program on Energy and Sustainable Development - Powerpoint Slide Printouts (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - M3 Japanese Vis Sept 22-23 '04 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - NVC Spent Fuel, Materials (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cyber Sec (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Wenlandt Cyber Sec (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cybersecurity (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cybersecurity Dec 18 mtg 10 --> NSF Proposal (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - DHS Conf (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - May Chron 2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - May Chron 2004 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pub Policy + Nvc Threat PPNT meeting 1/27-1/28/05 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1 DHS mtg 1/31/05 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - DHS mtg Monterey 2/07/05 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Upcoming Shorenstein Forum Seminars (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - RAND 4/12 + 13/2005 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - LBL Envir. Energy Technologies Div. Review Cmte. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Pearlstein Seminar (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bob Powell (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Summit conf + Unceleb June 23-25/05 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sustainable Dev. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Haldeman, Zack - visit (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - CEIP 7/14/05 WDP (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - ANS meeting San Diego 6/5-9/05 att. 6/7/05 present (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Mary May (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - May Meetings 2004 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Nucl Pol Res Inst 1/25-27/2004 W,DC5 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - US-China Econ + Sec. Rev. Comsn Feb 12-13 2004 UCSD (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - March 1 2004 @CISAC, UN Conf. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - WIIS at CISAC Meeting 3/12/04 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Carnegie Visit to CISAC 3/18/04 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - APS Meeting 3/22-3/26/2004 Montreal (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - IGERT July 20-22 04 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Carnegie Conf, June 21-22, 04 WDC (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - AmAss Physics Teachers Aug 04 Sacram (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - CISAC Summer Study Aug 17-18 2004 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Lake Tahoe Environmental Sciences Center + Diplomatic Academy Oct 20-22 2004 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - ElBaradei Visit 2004 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Mensa 11/27/04 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Pac Coon. Mem. Retreat Nov. 11-13, 2004 Santa Monica CA (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Atoms for Peace LLNL 1/24/03 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - PESD @ SU Feb 19+20 03 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Pres. 3/13/03 LMCO 4pm (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - MIIS Talk 3/31/03 Cancelled (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Alumni Day SU May 17, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - ANS Talk UCSD 6/4/03 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - June 19-20 03 Intelligence Predictability (Sagan conf.) (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Atoms for Peace 5/26-29/03 Tokyo (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - SU CISAC Summer WS 18-22 Aug 03, Fissile Mat'l Agenda (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - IGCC UCSD FS Program 7/28/2003 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Atoms for Peace 7/16-7/25/03 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - LLNL Nov 13-14 03 Atoms for Peace (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Geopolitics of Natural Gas (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Topoff 2 Conf 05/07/03 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - PAC Council Memb Wknd Westin Harbor Island San Diego 11/5-7/99 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Int'l Coop to Combat Crime + Terrorism, Dec. 6+7, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Trip Dec. 99 London Paris (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Export Control Conf May 3, 00 CISAC (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - LLNL Mar 7-2000 Las Vegas (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - UCSD Talk 4/17/00 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - NAS Talk WDC 4/30/00 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Ethnic Profiling + Civil Rights of Asian Am. in Tech LA 5/6/00 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Export Controls WS June 7, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - CFR June 9-10, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Exp. Nuc. E in a Grnhse. World 6/22-23/00 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - CTBT Rndtable SU 7/19/00 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - MACART Fnd. Mtg 7/28/00 Fut. of Sci/Sec Stds. Harvard (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - ISODARCO Sum. Course Rovereto Aug 9-18 2000a (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Oct. 16-18 00 Protocol Mtg CISAC (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Sci + Tech Comm of NATO Parliamentary Assem. (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - RAND BoT Hotel Casa del Mar Santa Monica 11/10/00 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - PCIP Mtg 11/17-18/2000 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Nov 2000 NMD (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - APARC KKD SU conf Dec 1 2000 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Dec 13-14 2000 LLNL Sr Rev Panel (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - CSIS (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - DC dblws IT + DPRK Apr 30 May 1 2001 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - globalizations Conf Stanford 7/29-31/2001 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - CSIS WDC 8/22-24/01 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Global 2001 Conf 9/01 France (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Herb York Tribute Nov 3 01 UCSD (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Dick Clarke Cyberterrorism 10/31/01 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - UCLA Nov 8 01 Intriligator (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - 12/12/01 US-Asian Policy Group (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - May 17 China Em Colloq 2002 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - LANL mtg June 5-6 02 Travel June 4 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - CSIS Dec 5-6, 2001 W, DC (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - CSIS (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - CSIS June 18 02 W DC (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Pugwash La Jolla Aug 2002 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Paris Sept 2002 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - RAND Bd of Trustees 11/15/02 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - PCIP Nov 15, 16 02 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - ISODARCO (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - MIIS Advisory WDC 11/16/02 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Paper - Grand Strategy (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Issues in Sci + Tech Isaacs + May article May 04 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Presentation M3 2005 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - McGraw Hill Permission (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - EP Paper 8/2003 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - NYTimes Letter-Editor 6/1/03 BunkerBusters (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - July 2-4, 98 Disposal of Weapons + Nuclear Waste, Lake Como, Italy (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Thank Yous/Glad Letters (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Foreign Affairs Article 2/98 (Submitted) (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - May Co-Teach (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - PS 138 Win 98-99 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - 1999-2000 193/293 EES + OR (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - PS 193/293 Fall 98-99 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - May CV (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Emeritus Appt (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - M. may Facult Rept. 92-93 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - M. May - Faculty Rept. 93-94 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - M. May - Faculty Rept. 94-95 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - M. May - Faculty Rept. 95-96 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Faculty Report 96-97 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Faculty Report 97-98 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Michael May Fac Rept 10/98 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - Fac Rept 98-99 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - 00-01 Fac Rept (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Faculty Report 03-04 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - M May 03/09/05 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - May WS Risk Communic. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Handouts (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Op Ed (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Agenda (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sent (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Papers, presn (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 02 CISAC Summer Study Container Study Grp (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 2002 CISAC Int'l Security Summer Institute (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Summer Study Notes Container (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - CISAC Summer Inst. 8/02 Container Study Handouts (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Summer Institute Stanford 2002 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - NRC one pager (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - CISAC May 20, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - NR Commun meetings (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - China Energy & Global Environment Project (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Handout 8-14-01 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Misc Travel 01 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Bechtel Proposal 6-00 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - China Energy Bechtel Report 5/99 + 7/99 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Bechtel Rept 5/1/00 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - China Project Proposals/Summaries (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Energy Policy (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Liaoning Prov. Agreement (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - China EGY & Glob Envl Proj Hubei Prov (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - EPRI China Energy (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Rockefeller Bros (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Joyce Mertz Gilmore (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - EPRI Agreement China Energy (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - China Energy Library Encina Hall (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - A/P Scholars (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - China Energy Student Assistants (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - China Project Update (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - China Energy Budget (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Heller Tour (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - China Energy Meeting After Mar 99 visit (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - EPRI QLY Prog Repts (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - China Energy Final Rept 11/02 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Shandong (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Elect. Deregul. Guangdong Prov. Prc (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Report WS 1 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 3rd China Workshop (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - 2/19/99 3rd China WS (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Environmental Engineering & Science (Teaching)
  - EES & OR Committee Assignments Nov. 2, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - DSC Material (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mergere Ext. Rel. Com. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - EES & OR Enrollment 99-2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - EES & OR Dept. Organization of the Affiliates Program (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - EES & OR Reapps (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - EES & OR Undergrad Program (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - IEEM - 5 year plan (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fall & Spring 1996 Syllabi (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - EES & OR - All Courses: Research & Other Sugg. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - EES & OR 1-293 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - EES & OR 1-270/1-293 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - EES & OR 1-270/1-293 Cont'd (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - EES & OR 1-270/1-293 Cont'd (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - EES & OR 1-270/1-293 Cont'd (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294 Cont'd. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Int'l Trade, Hitech Trade, Security (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - EES & OR 1-270/1-293 Nuclear "Proliferation" (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: World Energy Bckgd. Refs. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Trade & Ind. Policy Backgd./Refs. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Holzrichter Lecture (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Risk (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Climate (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Wrapups/Feedbacks (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Quizzes, Presentations (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Ozone Outline/Presentations (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - EES & OR 1-271/1-294: Student Papers (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - EES & OR 290 - 1997 2nd draw (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - EES & OR Seminar VGs 20 min. 11/26/96 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 2905 GM (5) VG (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - ES 290 - 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - EES 290 1993 (Also CISAC Sem PU 1993) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - EES 290 - 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 290 EES Sem 10/15/1992 May NW Presentation 10/92 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - EES Symp Spr93 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - EES 470 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - EN & Secur EES 493 5/27/98 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - PS 138 Win 98 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - PS 138 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - PS 38 1997-98 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - PS 38 Economic Security Var. Yrs. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Poli Sci 125 11/28/95 Power Relationships in Asia Over the Next Few Decades (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - PS 138B 91-94 Legacy of Cold War ++ (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Nucl Stabil. Harvey Mudd TCR + Vgs 11/13/91 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - PS 125 11/19/96 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - NW S & D Seminar SCCN 2/28/95 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - PS 138 Win 98/99 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - PS 138 - 99 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - PS 138 Win 2000 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 2001/2002 Winter Course Evals (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Michael May Curriculum Vitae (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - May Retirement (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - IE-EM Department, EES & OR Department 5 year plan (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - EES & OR Misc. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - EES & OR Financial (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - EES & OR 094Q (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 98 Soph Seminar Masters (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - How a Nuclear Plant Works (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Soph Sem Spr Q 99-2000 Nuc Iss Today (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Soph Sem 02-03 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Soph Sem 03-04 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Weapons Policy (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Strategic Plan (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Container Security (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Nuke Posture Rev Alt 2002 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - CV (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - M3 Research Int. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - May Retirement (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - May Photo (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - APS Fellowship (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Chyba (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Cote (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Sid Drell (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Gallucci (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Grigorian Visit to CISAC (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Isaka (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Pitch Johnson (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Hans Mark (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - McCracken, Michael (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Ortoli (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Peck (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Pene (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Rothwell's Proposal (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 11/16/99 Nvc Future Vic Reis (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Tian, J (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Wilkening 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Annual Report (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Grant (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Pub Com Current (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - May Bio (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Winter 98 Team Teaching (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - AAAS (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - A/PARC (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - American Nuclear Society (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - IMAI Letter (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Marshall Legacy Institute (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - CISAC 25th Reunion Conf. (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Ctr for Int'l Cooperation Space Stanford University (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - The Greenhouse Debate - A. Manne (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Restructuring (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Council on FOR REL (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - PCIP (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - DOE Internships 7/1/98 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - LLNL (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - MOFTEC Visit? July 12-17 98 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - IR (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Nat. Acad. of Science (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Nuclear Energy/Security Proj. (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Quintell (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - RAND (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Sigma Xi (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Silicon Valley Defense Space Consortium (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - SPO Grant Report (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - WAIS (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Undergrad Research (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - World Bank (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - (DoJ) Counterterrorism Management (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Energy and Security in East Asia (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Impact on Global Warming of Development and Structural Changes in the Electricity Sector of Guangdong Province, China (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - The Cox Committee Report: An Assessment (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - The U.S. Enlargement Strategy and Nuclear Weapons (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - N. Korea Agreed Framework - Strategic Comments Vol 7 No. 6 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Washington Quarterly Sum '97 Vol 20 No 3 May letter to Editor (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Communicating Nuclear Risk: Informing the Public About the Risks and Realities of Nuclear Terrorism (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - American Scientist Nov-Dec 1994 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Eng 9-99 --> (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - EES OR 193/293 Aut 98 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - EES + OR Admin (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - EES + OR 193 Fall 97 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - EES + OR Retreat (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - 1997-98 Spring Soph Sem (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Annual Certification Complaince Form EES/OR (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - EES/OR Memos (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Vision Comm Engineering (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - EES/OR Memos (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - IIS Annual Report (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Distance Learning Initiative (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - IR (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - DPRK WS 2 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - CISAC Agendas/Corres (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Senior Fellow (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - IIS Sen. Fellow Courtesy Appt 5/99 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - IAEA Dept of Safeguards - Guidelines (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Meetings, Grants, Proposals
  - Feb 5 1998 CISAC agenda (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - CFR 2/9/98 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - A/PARC Corp Affil March 12-13 1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)